# **BRECKA BROWN, MPS-TM**

Philadelphia, Pa - (609) 477-6797 - Sb1417@Georgetown.edu

As a data enthusiast, working in the non-profit sector, I have repeatedly advocated for affordable living, education, housing, and technology. I have been able to demonstrate my commitment to equality by working on high priority initiatives including the Affordable Care Act, Housing First, ELECT, and ITWorks. With over 9 years of experience in data management and data analytics for web-based applications, databases, and compliance across state, city, county, and federal agencies, I am seeking a position where I can utilize my expertise in data management, analysis, and strategy to drive meaningful outcomes in your organization.

#### **EDUCATION**

Georgetown University | M.P.S. in Technology Management (May 2017) Washington, D.C.

Fairleigh Dickinson University | B.A. in Business & Technology (June 2009) Teaneck, N.J.

Mercer County Community College | A.A.S. in Computer Networking & System Administration (May 2005) West Windsor, N.J.

#### TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

**Software:** Microsoft Suite (Excel, Access, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook, Projects) Google Apps

Databases: LACES, AWARDS, CIS-DM, SchoolNET,

HMIS, ADP, PostgreSQL

*Operating Systems:* Windows, Linux, iOS

Visualization Tools: Google Data Studio, Tableau,

Power BI

**Certifications**: Microsoft Certified Microsoft Excel Expert

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## PATH, INC |Philadelphia, PA Supervisor of Support Services

January 2020 - Present

Notable Accomplishment: Created and implemented a data system to allow client data to be shared across multiple departments, improving collaboration between departments. Created and implemented a tracking system to monitor the petty cash spent at 38 sites. Using insight derived from data, reduced the funds used by each site by an average of \$200 a month. Reduced the amount of paper used for blank forms by 20%

- Led a team of 6 staff members while remote throughout the pandemic: Accountant, QI Specialist, Scheduling Coordinator, and Three Administrative Secretaries. Hired and trained two accountants.
- Manage more than \$446k in Rep Payee and Non-Rep Payee funds
- Oversaw interactions with Social Security Administration including monitoring Social Security correspondence and actions required for follow up.
- Manage time and attendance using ADP for a staff of 200 members which includes identifying, reconciling, researching, and resolving data discrepancies
- Used PostgreSQL to query data and build reports

A Woman's Place (AWP)| Doylestown, PA

Data System Developer & Consultant; (5-month contract)

August 2019 - January 2020

Notable Accomplishment: Created a system to render key program performance data centrally accessible in real-time for data-driven decision making, regulatory reporting, and seeking new funding sources.

- Met with directors to define key program metrics
- Built a data management system to collect, aggregate, centralize, and visualize defined metrics
- Utilized Google Apps to build data dashboards and data tracking systems
- Researched data management tools to find an inexpensive solution to suit AWP's needs

#### Tech Impact | Philadelphia, PA Senior Instructor; ITWorks

November 2018 - August 2019

Notable Accomplishment: Reviewed historical program data for patterns. Derived insight which resulted in program minimum grade requirement modification to better prepare students for CompTIA A+ certification.

- Instructed accelerated IT program using the Cisco IT Essentials curriculum and the CompTIA A+ objectives
- Wrote new curriculum based on 2019 CompTIA A+ objectives
- Maintained certification computer lab including equipment, software, licensing, and network infrastructure
- Managed application process of 100+ applicants every six months, requiring phone, group, and individual interviews to fill class roster of 18
- Tracked and monitored student attendance, grades, and timesheets

## Communities in Schools (CIS) | Philadelphia, PA Data Coordinator & Manager; ELECT & Nationals CIS

March 2018 - October 2018

Notable Accomplishment: Created customized data report cards for each case manager for a twelve-member team which identified missing or inaccurate data entries, resulting in 100% data compliance.

- Senior data manager over four separate enrollment databases in fast-paced, compliance-heavy environment
- In charge of FERPA compliance validation between databases on district, nationals, and stakeholder platforms
- In charge of collecting and submitting data and documentation for licensing renewal via national's database
- Processed clearances and reported eligibility requirements for over 400 students
- Submitted to CIS board key metrics on CIS student status based on data from enrollment, pregnancy, attendance, GPA, and other data points for quarterly reports
- Managed PostgreSQL Database, queried data for weekly, monthly, quarterly, and ad hoc reports.

# Center for Family Services | Camden, N.J. (employed for 5 years and 10 months) Data Manager; Camden Corps Plus

July 2016 - March 2018

Notable Accomplishment: Went above my duties as Data Manager to successfully negotiate with the neighborhood delicatessen to offer program participants reduced price lunch options. The access to affordable lunch options had a positive impact on student focus and after break tardiness. Spotlighted in company's internal news share for great work.

- Senior data manager for collaboration with Rutgers University, Camden County Community College, and Center for Family Services proprietary databases LACES and Awards
- Aggregated data to support completion of the Department of Labor (DOL) monthly reports and supported data sharing and collection with the department
- Submitted participant payroll to finance and kept records of all payments and participant pay rates
- Developed and introduced formula for tracking student performance integrated with Google Apps to give

teachers and administrators transparent information on how scores were calculated

Served as a compliance manager for WIOA guidelines to facilitate sending documents to One Stop

Center for Family Services | Camden, N.J. Lead Intake Counselor; Housing First Program Admin/Intake Counselor; Housing First Program

May 2015 - July 2016 May 2012 - May 2015

Notable Accomplishment: Researched and informed the IT department about the need to sign and accept the business associate agreement with Google Apps to confirm that the use of Google products did not violate HIPAA regulations. This ensured that the agency would be able to utilize the benefits of Google Apps while protecting sensitive client data and avoiding fines and penalties associated with HIPAA violations.

- Maintained a caseload of between 7 to 14 clients, completed intake and aggregated HMIS data
- Submitted monthly reports on program enrollment and participant eligibility criteria to funders for city, state, and county grants
- Advocated for clients by writing promissory notes to send to landlords to vouch for their program eligibility, completing check requests, and contacting hotels/motels for emergency stay

# Center for Family Services | Camden, N.J. Affordable Care Act Navigator; Federal Marketplace

September 2013 - May 2015

Notable Accomplishment: Implemented a data management system that cut data processing time by more than 50% enrolled 50 people in the Affordable Care Act early in its launch.

- Responsible for bringing the Affordable Care Act marketplace online for seven counties in New Jersey
- Created linked excel workbooks to auto-calculate weekly, monthly, and quarterly metrics for a staff of seventeen
- Met with clients to provide support and education on the marketplace and provide additional training
- Trained staff to use portable scanning, printing technologies and Microsoft Surface tablets